Hannah McCain

Senior Frontend Developer

Hannah is a senior full stack **JavaScript/TypeScript** developer with particular expertise on the front end. She has over 5 years of experience with **React**, is proficient with multiple **CSS** libraries, and is comfortable dipping into the back end whenever needed.

CONTACT

+1 207 632 7715 hannahjmccain@gmail.com 29 E. University Blvd Tucson, AZ, 85705

EDUCATION

Thinkful
New York, New York (remote)
Intensive full-stack bootcamp, 2016

Lewis & Clark College Portland, Oregon B.A., Religious Studies, 2012

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript

TypeScript

CSS

Tailwind CSS

SQL

Node.js

GraphQL

NON-TECHNICAL SKILLS

Excellent communication skills

Experience in enterprise, startup, and B2B settings

Proficient in French, Spanish

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance - Senior Frontend Developer
Remote • March 2022 - present

- Typescript, React, CSS, Tailwind CSS
- Working as frontend developer and/or consultant on a freelance/contract basis.
 - Primary frontend developer on the latest release of Bit.io database solution. Used React and Tailwind CSS to update the UI for improved user experience.

Classy - Senior Software Engineer
San Diego, California (remote) • July 2021 - March 2022

- TypeScript, React, CSS, GraphQL
- Senior developer co-leading the development of an internal design system.
 - Completed frontend component audit.
 - Built reusable React components and released them as an NPM library for internal testing.
 - Technical point of contact and JavaScript mentor for frontend developers.

Covetrus - Senior Software Engineer
Portland, Maine (remote) • March 2018 - July 2021*
 * Promoted 2020 to Senior level

- TypeScript, React, CSS, GraphQL, Java
- Worked on a React/TypeScript prescription- and appointment-management web application used by thousands of veterinary practices.
- Front-end lead for a new internationalized React/TypeScript prescription- and appointment-management web application.
 - Made front-end architecture decisions including defining code structure, choosing libraries, and organizing repo.
 - Established code standards/best practices.
- Primary developer on internal design system library.
 - Built monorepo using Lerna and Yarn Workspaces.
 - Built NPM publishing pipeline for design system components using Rollup.js.
 - Technical point of contact and JavaScript mentor for UX developers.